payoneer.com 2019-12-31

# Privacy Policy | Payoneer

## APPENDIX 1: ADDITIONAL TERMS FOR EEA CUSTOMERS

**The information below is required pursuant to the EEA law regarding privacy and data protection. The terms below apply to EEA customers in addition to the terms in the rest of the Policy.**

For the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation (“ **GDPR”** ), the data controller is Payoneer EU Limited of 57/63 Line Wall Road, Gibraltar, a company established in Gibraltar and regulated for data protection purposes by the Gibraltar Regulatory Authority (“Payoneer EU”). If you have any questions about this Policy, please contact our Data Protection Officer (DPO) at [DPO@payoneer.com](mailto:DPO@payoneer.com).

If you are unhappy about how we are processing your data or how we have responded to a request or complaint, you have the right to make a complaint to the Gibraltar Regulatory Authority (GRA) or your local supervisory authority.  You can find more details about how to contact the GRA on their website <https://www.gra.gi/data-protection>.

## WHEN DO WE SHARE YOUR INFORMATION

The table headed  ** _“How and Why We Share Your Information”_**  in the main part of the Policy under the heading  **“WHEN DO WE SHARE YOUR INFORMATION”**  lists who we may share your information with, which include transfers for reasons of legal compliance and necessity in order to provide you with our Services.

You should be aware that when sharing your information, it may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the EEA.

Please note that where data is transferred outside of the EEA, non-EEA countries may not offer the same level of protection for personal data as is available in the EEA. Payoneer will take various measures to ensure that your data is treated securely, which may include, but not be limited to:

assessing the security measures taken at any place your data is transferred to;

having suitable contract terms in place that oblige a data processor to only process in accordance with our instructions; and

having monitoring, reporting and resolution procedures in place with regard to ongoing security.

Please contact us if you require more detailed information about international transfers of your information, and the particular safeguards used.

## LEGAL GROUNDS FOR PROCESSING YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We process your information based on the following legal grounds, as recognised by and in compliance with the applicable data protection laws:

the processing is necessary to perform our contract with you (i.e. the Terms and Conditions that apply as applicable with respect to Payoneer Services, for the provision of our Services), or to take steps requested by you before entering into said contract;

the processing is in Payoneer’s or someone else’s legitimate interests, and these interests are not overridden by your interests or rights in the protection of your personal data. This may include processing your data for prevention of fraudulent activity, internal research and analytics assessments, for purposes of communication with you, and informing you about new products and services we are offering or to promote new products and services of other parties which we think may be of interest to you, etc.;

you have given your consent to the processing of your data;

the processing is necessary to meet a legal obligation which applies to Payoneer.

Sometimes we process data about you which the law considers to fall within special categories (see section “What data do we process about you?” for more details), in which case, we use one of the following grounds:

the processing is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims;

you have freely given your informed, specific consent to the processing; or

the processing is necessary for reasons of substantial public interest, based on applicable law.

If you would like more information about the legal grounds used to process your information, or about the legitimate interests referred to above, please contact us.

In cases where we have asked for, and you have given, your consent to our processing of your personal data, you have the right to withdraw such consent at any time.  You can do this by contacting our DPO at  _[DPO@payoneer.com](mailto:DPO@payoneer.com)_.

## DO YOU HAVE TO GIVE US YOUR INFORMATION?

In most cases, providing your personal data to us is optional, however, if you do not provide it, you will not be able to use our Services. For example, we need details such as your name, address and bank account details so that we can make payments to you and receive payments from you. In other cases, you have a choice over whether we collect your personal data, for example, you can turn off cookies on your browser and we will not place any cookies on your device or computer (although in this case you may not be able to use all parts of our website).

## PROFILING AND AUTOMATED DECISION MAKING

We use automated decision making as part of our process to evaluate eligibility for the use of the Payoneer Services. We use these tools as a measure of fraud prevention and for purposes of security and risk assessment relating to the performance of the Payoneer Services:

Automated tools incorporated in our process of approval of your registration application: based on the information you provided, the tool may advise if additional information is required for purpose of approval of your application.

Automated tools incorporated in our process of approval of certain payment transaction of registered users: such tools may advise if additional information is required for purpose of performance of the payment transaction.

## HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION?

Payoneer retains your information as required by applicable laws or regulations and/or in accordance with Payoneer’s internal policies and procedures for purposes of prevention of fraudulent activity, risk management and security. Payoneer will periodically review the necessity of retention of your data.

## EEA CUSTOMERS ONLY: YOUR RIGHTS UNDER GDPR

You have several rights in relation to your personal data which are described in more detail below.  You can exercise your rights at any time by contacting us at [ _DPO@payoneer.com_](mailto:DPO@payoneer.com).

**Accessing your data**

You can ask us to:

Confirm whether we are processing your personal data

Give you a copy of that data

Provide you with other information about your personal data such as what data we have, what we use it for, who we disclose it to, whether we transfer it abroad and how we protect it, how long we keep it for, what rights you have, how you can make a complaint, where we got your data from and whether we carry out any automated decision making or profiling.  We aim to give you all this information in this privacy policy, although if anything is unclear, please contact our Data Protection Officer at [ _DPO@payoneer.com_](mailto:DPO@payoneer.com).

You do not have to pay a fee for a copy of your information unless your request is unfounded, respective or excessive, in which case we will charge a reasonable amount in the circumstances.  We will let you know of any charges before completing your request.

We aim to respond to you within 1 (one) month of receiving your request unless it is particularly complicated or you have made several requests, in which case we aim to respond within 3 (three) months.  We will let you know if we are going to take longer than 1 (one) month in dealing with your request.  If we have a lot of information about you we might ask you if you can tell us what exactly you want to receive.  This will help us action your request more quickly.

**Correcting your data**

You can ask us to correct any data which is inaccurate or incomplete.  This is free of charge.

If we have shared the data with anyone else, we will tell them about the correction wherever possible.  We aim to deal with requests for correction within 1 (one) month, although it might take us up to 3 (three) months if your request is particularly complicated.

If we cannot action a request to correct your data, we will let you know and explain why this is.

**Erasing your data**

This right is sometimes referred to as “the right to be forgotten”.  This is not an absolute right but you have the right to have your data erased, free of charge, in certain circumstances.

You can ask for your data to be erased where:

it is no longer necessary for the purpose for which it was originally collected or processed;

we are processing your data based on your consent, and you withdraw that consent;

you object to the processing and we do not have an overriding legitimate interest for continuing;

your data has been unlawfully processed;

your data must be erased to comply with a legal obligation;

the data was processed to offer information society services to a child.

There are some exceptions to this right.  If one of these applies, we do not have to delete the data.

If we have shared your data with third parties, we will tell them about the erasure of your data unless this is impossible or would involve disproportionate effort.

**Restricting the processing of your data**

You can ask us to restrict the processing of your personal data in some circumstances, free of charge.  This is not an absolute right.  If processing is restricted we can store the data and retain enough information to make sure the restriction is respected, but we cannot further process your data.

You can restrict the processing of your personal data in the following cases:

if you contest the accuracy of your data, we will restrict processing until we have made sure the data is accurate;

if you object to our processing and we are considering this objection;

if the processing is unlawful but you do not want us to erase your data;

if we no longer need the personal data but you require the data to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim.

If we have disclosed the data to a third party, we will inform them about the restriction unless it is impossible or would require a disproportionate effort.  We will tell you if we decide to lift a restriction on processing your data.

**Objecting to the processing of your data**

Objecting to the processing of your data is free of charge.  It is not an absolute right but you can object to our processing of your data where it is:

based on the legitimate interests ground; or

for the purposes of scientific/historical research and statistics.

We will stop processing your personal data unless we have compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests and rights, or unless we are processing the data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

You can require us to stop using your data for direct marketing purposes.  We will stop as soon as we receive your request.  There are no exemptions or reasons for us to refuse.

**Data Portability**

This allows you to obtain and reuse your personal data for your own purposes across different services.  It applies where the following conditions are met:

you provided the personal data to us yourself;

we are processing the data either based on your consent or because it is necessary for the performance of a contract; and

the processing is carried out by automated means.

We will provide your data free of charge in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable form.  We aim to provide your data within 1 (one) month of receiving your request unless it is particularly complicated or you have made several requests, in which case we aim to respond within 3 (three) months.  If we are going to take longer than 1 (one) month we will let you know and explain why we need more time.  If we consider that we cannot provide you with your data, we will contact you and explain why this is.

**Automated decision making and profiling**

You have the right not to be subject to a decision which is based on automated processing and which produces a legal (or similarly significant) effect on you.

We will tell you about any automated decision making that affects you.  You have the right to:

request human intervention;

express your point of view;

ask for the decision to be explained; and

challenge the decision.

These rights are not absolute.  They do not apply if the decision is:

necessary for us to enter into or perform a contract with you;

authorised by law (e.g. for fraud prevention); or

based on your explicit consent.
